# DANIEL BARKER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **ABOUT ME**

As a graduate of Nashville Software School, I have experience in full stack web development. I have learned to utilize my skills from being a collegiate athlete to instill discipline and iterative improvement within my personal software development. I am able to collaborate across different areas of product development to fulfill my role within a team. I was introduced to software development by a family member, and began doing some independent study. My interest in this field led me to NSS and my drive helped me complete the program with a passion for continued learning. I'm expanding upon my current knowledge by attending local coding meetups and completing independent personal projects.

## **CONTACT DETAILS**



(615) 626-7426



barkerdanny17@yahoo.com



linkedin.com/in/daniel-97-barker/



github.com/DannyBarker

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- React
- Python
- Django

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Developer, Nashville Software School (2019)

- Front End (HTML, CSS, Javascript, React)
- Back End (Django & Python)

Middle Tennessee State University (2017-2019)

Biology major & Chemistry minor

Martin Methodist (2016-2017)

- Biology major & Chemistry minor
- · Played varsity soccer

#### **SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE**

Nashville Software School

- Full-time 6 month program that taught full-stack fundamentals
- · Developed applications using HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Python, and Django

(2019)

- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs with persistent data stores
- · Effectively collaborated with other developers using Git and Github
- · Leveraged DRY, modular, and reusable code principles.
- · Designed databases using entity-relationship diagrams (ERDs)
- Utilized Agile techniques in group-based projects to simulate best practices

## **Projects**

Shannon's Hair Shoppe

React-App

I created an app for a small-business hair salon using React. I used ReactStrap for user-friendly modals and react-datetime for scheduling easy appointments. I implemented a customizable and feature-rich admin calendar view using Fullcalendar. One goal of this app was to automate Shannon's manual processes for booking and managing appointments. Repo link: https://github.com/DannyBarker/Hair-Shop-Cap

- · Two types of users (non-admin/admin)
  - · Non-Admins:
    - Request appointments
    - See personal profile
    - See upcoming appointments (filtered by date/time)
    - Delete and edit requested appointments
    - See denied appointments and the reason
    - See past haircuts and stylist notes
  - · Admins:
    - Accept/deny requested appointments
    - · Give reasons for denied appointments
    - See all non-admin profiles
    - See appointments in list view or calendar view
    - Cancel appointments
    - Add and edit stylists' notes to finished appointments

Redono

Web-App

I created this app for users to donate old gift cards to charity. I used Django framework to create the backend along with a SQLlite database. Django templates were used to present the data to the user. I leveraged Folium and Seaborn to make the map report of the regions where gift cards were donated. A pickle file that contained the polygon coordinates of zip codes was layered on top of the map to give zip code region shapes. Repo link: https://github.com/DannyBarker/backEndCapstone2.0

- Two types of users (non-company/company)
  - · Non-Company:
    - Donate a giftcard
    - View and edit past donations
  - · Company:
    - View total amount donated from gift cards
    - See donations in a color categorized map

#### OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

### Head Soccer Coach/Instructor

(2014 - Present)

Aris FC & LPG Sports Academy

- Lead player development for ages 9 18 years
- Structure practice and game outlines
- Work with a wide range of parents, players, and directors to meet player goals
- · Design and lead one-on-one skill sessions

### Cheddar's Scratch Kitchen

(Feb. 2017 - March 2019)

Server & Cooking's Assistant

- · Trained new servers and cook assistants
- · Prepared food and waited tables